PRAVEEN KUMAR ARUMUGAM

Contact: 9600501281; Email ID: Praveenap24hrs@amail.com

Linked In: linkedin.com/in/praveenkumar0505

HR Consultant with full cycle recruiting and coordinating experience into IT Staffing. Communicates and collaborates effectively with both candidates and clients by relying on Industry knowledge and Interpersonal skills. Maintains a positive attitude under pressure and is naturally adept at building relationships at all levels.

EXPERIENCE:

HR CONSULTANT – LEVEL 2 – RECRUITMENT, CAREERNET TECHNOLOGIES,

RPO COORDINATOR | ONSITE - COMCAST CORPORATION, Chennai.

MAR 2022 - Till Date

- Working closely with the stakeholders to effectively coordinate, schedule, plan and manage project management activities.
- Conduct structured business needs discussion with hiring managers before search commences, identifying the key role and candidate requirements and agreeing the sourcing and selection strategy, respective roles and responsibilities and timelines.
- Scheduling interviews and assessments, coordinating candidate, hiring manager, blocking calendars and sending invites (Teams)
- Regular follow up on the interview schedules and reschedules.
- Maintain recruitment applicant tracking system ensuring information is up-to-date and updating spreadsheets on a timely manner.
- Conducting HR discussions, generate offer proposals/packages and ensure all required approvals are obtained before offers are made. Deliver offer to candidates and negotiate offers between hiring managers and candidates.
- Effectively manage general queries from candidates, hiring managers and sourcing team.
- Produce ad hoc recruiting weekly and monthly reports.
- Managing the relationship with the recruiting team for smooth flow of profiles.
- Driving a high level of stakeholder satisfaction.
- Regular follow ups with already hired candidates until they join.

HR CONSULTANT - LEVEL 2 CAREERNET TECHNOLOGIES, Chennai

IT RECRUITEMENT

JUNE 2021 - FEB 2022

- Determines applicant requirements by studying job description.
- Review and understand technical job requirement.
- Hiring candidates on **permanent positions** for **IT Requirements**.
- Source potential candidates on platforms like Naukri, LinkedIn and internal database.
- Screening candidates based on job description and job qualifications to analyze the applicant's abilities.
- Keeping track of selected candidates joining date in the company & get the confirmation of the same from company on joining date of the candidates.
- Maintain cordial relationship with the candidate for further references.
- Recruiting candidates for permanent positions.
- Follow up with candidates and On-boarding New Hires.

Major client supported:

Fresh works, AppviewX, CondeNast,F5 Networks, Hubilo, Reliance Jio, Comcast (Current)

INTERNSHIP DETAILS:

Associate HR consultant | CAREERNET

MAR 2021 - MAY 2021

RESPONSIBILITIES HANDLED:

- Responsible for full recruitment cycle of Sourcing, Screening, Evaluating the CV's according to the requirement, Salary negotiation to the acceptance of the offer & final placement.
- Hiring candidates on **permanent positions** for **IT Requirements.**
- Responsible for providing best of the candidates to the client with the Minimum possible turnaround time.
- Making sure candidates join the organization on the given date & with less number of offer declines.

EDUCATIONAL CREDENTIALS:

• MBA (Computer Science in Engineering) from Sathyabama Institute of Science and Technology Business Incubator, Chennai

PERSONAL DETAILS:

• Date Of Birth :05 May 1996

• Marital Status: Single

• Languages Known: Tamil, English

• Present Address: Velachery, Chennai